父さんはこちらで元気にやっている
Daddy's doing fine.
今は帰れないが
I can't come home yet,
いつか　家族四人で暮らせる日を指折り数えて待っているよ
but I'm counting the days until the four of us can live as a family again.
それまでは　真砂子
Until then, Masako...
父さんの代りに　万里夫を守ってやってくれ
Keep Mario safe in my place.
お父様　真砂子頑張るからね
Father, I will not disappoint you.
きっとマリオさんを守り切るわ
I won't let anything happen to Mario.
あの人を絶対に　すり潰してみせるから
I will crush him at all costs.
少年少女輪になって
shounen shoujo wa ni natte
The boys and girls form a ring
伸ばした手は空を切って落ちる
nobashita te wa kuu wo kitte ochiru
Extended hands cut down through the air
交わらないイマジナリー
majiwaranai imaginary
The Imaginary and the Real can never mingle
回転木馬宙を舞って
kaiten mokuba chuu wo matte
The merry-go-round twirls into the air
戦いの幕を切って落とす
tatakai no maku wo kitte otosu
As the curtain of war is torn open
秘め事明かすホーリーナイト
himegoto akasu holy night
The Holy Night for divulging secrets
真夜中開く窓
mayonaka hiraku mado temaneku nazo no koe
My window opens at night and a mysterious voice beckons
手招く謎の声
深紅のカーテンを翻して
shinku no curtain wo hirugaeshite hohoemi kakusu
A crimson curtain conceals the smile
微笑み隠す
少年よ我に帰れ
shounen yo ware ni kaere
Boys, come back to me
特急列車乗っちゃって
tokkyuu ressha nocchate
I ended up getting on the midnight express
ネバーランドに連れてって
neverland ni tsuretette
Take me away to Neverland
一切合切奪ってよ
issai gassai ubatte yo
Steal away everything I have
後ろ指さされたって
ushiro yubi sasaretatte
I don't care if you talk behind my back
一目散に逃げちゃっていいよ
ichimokusan ni nigechatte iiyo
I'll just run away at full speed
全部お気に召すまま
zenbu oki ni mesu mama
Do as you please
少年少女輪になって
shounen shoujo wa ni natte
The boys and girls form a ring
伸ばした手は空を切って落ちる
nobashita te wa kuu wo kitte ochiru
Extended hands cut down through the air
回り始めるディステニー
mawari hajimeru destiny
Destiny begins to turn
本字幕由诸神字幕组（kamigami.org）制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听：hunter 翻译:草泥马 校对:冷漠的风  木落 时间轴:wcaster 压制:wcaster
嫌だわ　早くすり潰さないと
Gosh, I must crush him soon.
遂に手に入れた
I've finally got my hands on it.
これでマリオさんは
Now Mario will be...
巴里　巴里
これは
（麗しいの都　巴里）
What?!
明日の朝きっと　あなたは見つけるでしょう
素敵な歌声を楽しんでいただけたかしら
（冷たい石畳み　散る薔薇の花）
I hope you enjoyed my sweet voice.
お馬鹿さん　これは真赤な偽物
Silly girl.
It's an elaborate replica.
女優を甘く見ないことね
Don't underestimate actresses.
やるわね
Impressive.
善後策を考えなくては
I must come up with a counterattack strategy.
Renjaku! Fire!
連雀　火事を
私の朝は一杯の紅茶から始まる
My morning starts with a single cup of black tea.
紅茶と男は初摘みに限る
Men are like tea: the first cup is always the most satisfying.
では　引き続き高倉冠葉とその妹の監視を頼むわよ
Please continue monitoring Kanba Takakura and his sister.
はい　お嬢様
Yes, Milady.
ところで　冠葉の新しい女は
By the way, who's his new girl?
くだんの金額　　（これは執事の連雀）
This is Renjaku, my maid.
祖父の代から夏芽家に仕える　私が唯一信頼置く者だ
She has been employed by the Natsume Clan since my grandfather's era.
The sole person I trust.
お嬢様　本日は
Milady, today is...
分かっているわ　役人会議だったわね
I know.
We have a board meeting today.
Good morning, President!
おはようございます　社長
おはよう
Good morning.
この男は夏芽佐兵衛　私の祖父だ
This man is Sahei Natsume.
My grandfather.
一代でこの夏芽ホールディングスを築いた
He built Natsume Holdings from scratch.
日本経済界のカリスマだ
A charismatic upstart in the Japanese financial world.
Grandfather
私は祖父の遺産を引き継ぐ形で　この地位に就いたのだ
I inherited his wealth to get to where I am now.
Grandfather
え　ドルは売り　ユーロは買って
Yes, sell the Dollars, buy Euros.
Don't let your guard down.
油断しないで　レートは生き物だから
The market has a mind of its own.
狼は生きろ　豚は死ね
It's a dog eat hog world.
ちょっと待って
Hold on.
この数字は何
What's with these numbers?
何分　最近アジアのレートが上がり
The Asian rates have increased latel-
使えない
You're useless!
お前みたいな男は　チャイナマネーにやられちゃいな
Men like you should just get Genghis conned!
To'oh General Hospital
Himari! I got Shoma to make Ben-to for you.
ひまり　今日は晶馬に弁当を作らせたぞ
There's octopus wieners too-
タコさんウィンナーもある
How electrifying.
痺れるな　編み物か
Knitting, huh?
Adult Knitting
Gator Scarf
男の人って　どんな色が好きかな
I wonder what colors boys like.
僕ならこれかな
I like this one.
そっか　大人っぽいな
I see. Grownup taste.
何をいってるんだい
What are you talking about?
You're a grownup, too.
君だって　もう大人じゃないか
Grownup!
大人です　痺れました
That was electrifying!
あ　冠ちゃん
Ah! Kan!
じゃあ　僕は午後の回診があるから
See you. I have to make my afternoon rounds.
何してたんだ
What are you up to?
内緒
It's a secret!
なんだよ　内緒って
What's that supposed to mean?
冠ちゃんには関係ないでしょ
It's none of your business!
あいつは主治医だが　あまりいい人間じゃない
He may be your doctor, but he's one shady dude.
Don't talk to him unless you have to.
余計な事は話すな
なんでそんな事言うの
Why would you say something like that?
He's a nice person!
先生いい人だよ　ダブルエイチにマフラー届けてくれたし
He even sent my scarves to Double-H.
そんな人の悪口言う冠ちゃんなんて　嫌い
I hate you for badmouthing such a nice person!
そう　口論を
Trouble in paradise? I see.
それはいい兆候ね
That's a pleasant surprise.
引き続き　監視を頼むわね
Continue monitoring them.
今日はこの娘をマークしてみよう
I'll try tailing the girl today.
何故冠葉様はこの凸娘に惹かれているのか
Why is Master Kanba so taken with this forehead-chick?
その訳を探ることも私の使命
It is my duty to find out.
Survival Strategy
Welcome to Rock'n Roll Night
Welcome to Rock'n Roll Fight
I'm just a Rock'n Roll Man
We're just a Rock'n Roll BAND
俺たちは道なりに　走り続けてきた
標識だらけの道を飛ばし続けていく
幾つもの町を抜け　歌い続けてきた
腑抜け野郎共を煽り続けていく
長い長い冬が溶けても風が吹く
今も今も激しく風が吹く
Imagine!
きっと何物にもなれないお前さんに告げる
Listen, you lowlife who will never amount to anything.
あれ　あれ　あれー
What? What?
What?!
How dare you spy on me with a camera.
コソコソと人の事隠し撮りしやがって
全ては夏芽家のためなのです
I'm doing it all for the Natsume Clan!
いい根性してるじゃないか
You've got guts, lady.
一句　盗撮で　お前の母ちゃん　泣いている
Verse: "Your peeping habit | So shameful, indeed, reduced | Your mother to tears."
Verse: "Please, I beg of you | Let me take your photograph | In that costume. Pretty please?"
一句　その姿　是非とも撮らせて　くださいな
字余り
Too many syllables.
Verse: "Just take your best shot | I'll turn the camera on you | Not a spot untouched."
一句　撮られたら　撮り返します　隅々に
一句　撮りましょう　脱いだら凄い　もしかして
Verse: "Lights! Camera! Action! | Perhaps, stripping you down | Will make it awesome."
Good, good!
いいよ　いいよ
私帰らせていただきます
I am taking my leave!
こんな毒のあるイリュージョンなんて　耐えられま　せんー
I can't take such a toxic illusion!
生存戦略　しましょうか
Let's initiate the Survival Strategy.
夢を見ていたのかしら
Was that a dream?
そう　口論を
Trouble in paradise? I see.
それはいい兆候ね
That's a pleasant surprise.
って　それはさっき聞いたわ
Wait, you just told me that!
何を寝ぼけてるの　しっかりして頂戴
Are you asleep on the job?
Get ahold of yourself!
Grandfather
夏芽佐兵衛
Sahei Natsume, my grandfather, was an unparalleled genius when it came to business...
私の祖父は経済人としては　並ぶものなき天才であったが
But, he was a failure as a human being.
人間としては　破綻していた
Masako - Natsume Mansion -- Grandfather's Room - When Grandfather was alive - That man ruled over my entire world. So I decided to crush him.
My morning starts with a single cup of black tea.
私の朝は一杯の紅茶から始まる
I like my women like I like my tea: the younger the better.
紅茶と女は初摘みに限る
やった　遂にやったわ
Yes! I've finally done it!
Father
お父様　真砂子頑張ったわよね
Father, I've done well, haven't I?
夢
A dream?
I will not be crushed!
すり潰されたりせんぞ
今日もまたあの男を殺す夢を見てしまった
I dreamt of killing him again.
Because, so long as he still lives, my father cannot return.
あの男が死なない限り　お父様はこの家に帰っておいでにならないから
でも　お父様　私近頃とても怖いの
But father, I'm scared of myself.
このままでは　本当にあの男を殺してしまうんじゃないかって
At this rate, I may really end up killing him.
お早うございます　社長
Good morning, President!
お早う　社員
Good morning, employees.
これから中国は成長するぞ
Chinese economic boom is coming.
それを読めぬ奴はチャイナマネーにやられちゃいな
Those who can't see that should just get Genghis conned!
Me
Hey Mr president watch out
Someone shot a blow dart at my neck?!
何者かがわしの首筋に吹き矢を
Oh my god
夢
A dream?
I will not be crushed!
すり潰されたりせんぞ
What of you
女とゴルフクラブ新しいものに限る
I like my women like I like my golf clubs: the newer the better.
What a problem  No problem for you
Hey Mr president watch out
Someone shot a golf ball at my head!
何者かがわしの米神にゴルフボールを打ち込みやった
Oh jesus
What  happened  NO!
夢
A dream?
すり潰されたりせんぞ
I will not be crushed!
I like my women like I like my fruit: tropical.
女と果物は南国産に限る
フルーツの盛り合わせでございます
Your assorted fruits.
私　マンゴー食べたい
Grandfather
I wanna mango.
Mango
Grandfather
Eat as many as you like.
いくつでも食べなさい
Grandfather
Mango
Hey Mr president watch out
何者かがフルーツの中にキングコブラを忍ばせておった
Someone slipped in a king cobra in my fruit basket!
Oh Mr president NO!
夢
A dream?
すり潰されたりせんぞ
I will not be crushed!
すり潰されたりせんー
Today's
Slogan
I can't be with you and I can't be nice to you.
僕はやっぱり荻野目さんとは一緒にいられないし
優しくも出来ない
That's the fate of our families.
僕らと君の家族は　そういうふうにしかなれない運命なんだよ
I won't give up, even if you refuse.
晶馬君が嫌だって言っても　諦めないから
After all, I am your stalker!
だって　あたしは晶馬君のストーカーなんだもの
Faith will
move mountains.
I'll change the fate.
あたしは運命を変えてみせる
That is very difficult.
それはとても難しいわ
He still has absolute control over us.
私達は今もあの男に支配されている
He thought there were only two kinds of people in the world:
あの男はこの世界には二種類の人間しかいないと考えていた
Winners and losers.
成功者と敗北者
That twisted mindset had tormented my father
でも　その考え方がお父様を追い詰め
to the point that he could no longer live in this mansion.
この家にいられなくしてしまったのよ
Masako - Natsume Mansion -- Living Room with the Fireplace - When Grandfather was alive pt.2 - That monster took things precious to me. He even tried to crush Mario.
This one and this one, too!
こいつも　こいつもだ
You're never going to get over him with these still lying around!
こんなものがあるから　未練が残るのだ
Burn!
燃やしてしまえ
N
a
t
s
u
m
e
M
a
r
i
o
M
a
s
k
o
What an idiot.
バカめが
That's...
それは
なになに
Lookie here.
"I can't come home yet,"
いまは帰れないが
いつか家族四人で暮らせる日を　　　（やめて　お爺様）
"but I'm counting the days"
No, Grandfather!
指折り数えて待っているよ　　　　　（お願い　やめて）
"until the four of us can live as a family again."
Please, no!
In your dreams!
なにを　世迷い言
Listen well. He is a loser.
いいか　あの男は負け犬
An embarrassment to the Natsume Clan.
夏芽家の恥曝し
He's a stinky, stinky poo!
臭い臭いうんこちゃんだ
見よ　このわしを
Just look at me!
I'm a strong man who can never be crushed.
わしは誰にもすり潰されん強い男だ
そろそろ　マリオにも夏芽家に相応しい男になれるよう訓練せねばな
Mario needs some training too, to become a man worthy of carrying the Natsume name.
Men of the Natsume Clan must never be crushed by anything!
夏芽家の男子たるもの　いかなる困難にもすり潰されてはならん
Look, Mario!
よく見ろ　　マリオ
These are the trials that the men of the Natsume Clan have challenged and persevered!
これぞ夏芽家歴々のムサ達が挑み耐え抜いた試練の数々の
Mr president
わしより強くなれ　マリオ
Become a strong man like me. Never be crushed!
決してすり潰されるな
In fact, crush them! Mario!
むしろすり潰すのだ　マリオ
How dreadful.
なんて恐ろしい
Mario will be killed if I don't do something.
このままでは　マリオさんは殺されてしまう
お父様も帰って来ない
Father isn't coming home either.
I've finally made up my mind to crush that man.
私今度こそあの男をすり潰すことにしたわ
たとえ未来永劫呪われることになっても
Even if I were to be cursed for all eternity.
I'll keep you company, if you're going to be cursed.
呪われるなら　一緒に呪われてやる
That is the bond binding us together.
それが俺達を繋ぐ絆だ
おい　帰ったぞ
Hey! I'm home!
Welcome home, Master Sahei.
御帰りなさいませ　佐兵衛様
It's a large haul!
今日は大量だぞ
ほれ
Behold!
Congratulations.
それはおめでとうございます
Head Chef, prepare to-
料理長　準備を
Wait!
待てぃ
せっかくの自分の獲物を他人にさばかしちゃ
My prey.
Stripped by someone else.
Sad face.
ふくれっつらにもなろうってもんだ
It is blowfish after all.
河豚だけに
You shall witness the legendary swordsmanship of the Natsume men!
そこでとくと見届けるがよい
夏芽家直伝の男の包丁さばきを
Prepare to die!
いざ
Done.
さあ　出来た  (Oh Mr preesident you are excellent)
Well then...
では　早速いただきまー
Chow time!
No Mr president it's dangerous
し　痺れる
E-Electrifying!
There was poison in the blowfish I stripped!
わしのさばいた河豚に毒が
Mr president come back
That night, my grandfather died.
その晩  祖父は死んだ
I didn't even have to lift a finger.
わたくしが手を下すまでもなく
Just like that.
あっさりと
However, the disappearance of my grandfather didn't bring my father back.
しかし  祖父が消えても父は帰ってこなかった
I'm sure it's his curse.
きっと　これは　あの男の呪いなのだ
His grudge to never allow us to be a happy family again.
最後まで私達家族を幸せにしまいという
Milady. Master Mario is not in his room.
真砂子様
マリオ様が寝室にいらっしゃらないのですが
Mario?
マリオさん
マリオさん  どこだの
Mario?
Where are you?
マリオさん
Mario?
Where could he have gone?
一体どこへ
Mario!
マリオさん　いったい何を
What exactly are you doing?
すり潰されたりせんぞ
I will not be crushed.
か　か　が
Masako.
真砂子よ　分かるか
Can't you recognize me?
わしだ　佐兵衛じゃ
It's me, Sahei.
Did you really think I was dead? You fool.
もう死んだ者とたかをくくっておったか　愚か者め
You must have thought you'd taken over the Natsume Clan, but not on my watch.
まんまと夏芽家を乗っ取ったつもりであろうが　そうはいかん
Look.
見よ　河豚と女は自分でさばくに限る
I like my blowfish like I like my women: stripped by me.
真の夏芽家当主を決定するためのディナーショーを始めよう
Let's begin the dinner show that will determine the true leader of the Natsume Clan.
One plate of blowfish sashimi stripped by a certified chef and
片方の皿は料理人のさばいたごく普通のふぐ刺し
another plate of blowfish sashimi stripped by me, with just a hint of poison.
もう片方の皿は、わしがさばいたピリット毒の効いたふぐ刺し
Whoever survives after eating a plate will lead the Natsume Clan.
どちらかを食らって
生き残った者が夏芽家の当主だ
Pick one, Masako.
さあ　真砂子
好きな方を選べ
ふん　度胸のないやつ
Coward.
Very well. I'll just make Mario eat.
まあ　よかろう　ならば　まずマリオに食わせるまで
さあ　どっちかな　わしのさばいたふぐは
I wonder which plate...
was stripped by me.
こっちかな
This one?
男は運をも味方にせねば　生き残れはしない
In order to survive, a real man must have the power to bend luck to his will.
Chow tim-
いざ食うべ
だめ
No!
If it means putting Mario's life in danger...
マリオさんを危険に晒すくらいなら
いっそ　いっそ　　私が
I'll... I'll just...
I might as well be hanged for a sheep as a lamb.
毒を食らわば皿までも
Hi young girl watch out
マリオさんに取り憑いたおじい様のさばいたふぐの毒が
The blowfish's poison stripped by Mario, possessed by Grandfather!
Hello.
はい
Isn't it electrifying?
痺れるだろう
Yes. Quite literally.
ええ　今まさに
Blowfish poison is known as tetrodotoxin.
ふぐの毒はテトロドトキシンと言って
It's approximately a thousand times more poisonous than potassium cyanide.
青酸カリの約千倍の威力を持つ猛毒で
A single milligram is capable of killing about 5000 mice.
一ミリグラムあたり　約五千マウスユニットの毒力があり
The poison is isolated in a blowfish's body,
ふぐの体にはこの毒がある部位とない部位があるわけだけど
but it can spread to safe parts if stripped carelessly.
へたにさばくと
毒が毒のない部位にまで移ってしまう危険性もあるんだ
So, you should never eat blowfish prepared by amateurs.
だから　絶対に素人が調理したふぐを食べちゃいけないよ
Yes. I've learned my lesson.
そうね　身を持ってよく分かったわ
Oh? Are you electrified already?
え　もう痺れちゃってるのかい
Yes.
え　でも　もういいの
But it doesn't matter.
これで　夏芽の呪いは
Now the Natsume curse is...
Did you see, Father?
お父様　ご覧になって
I kept Mario safe to the end.
真砂子は立派にマリオさんを守り切りました
Oh, Father, I just wanted to hear it one last time...
だから　お父様　　一言　私に
that you love me.
愛してると言って欲しかった
No, actually...
いいえ　ホントは私はお父様じゃなくて
I wanted to hear from...
When did I...
何時の間に
Father?
お父様
Father!
お父様　　お父さまー
Kanba?
冠葉
Kanba!
冠葉　やつらに近づかないで
Stay away from them!
They'll just use you and toss you when they're done, just like my father!
このままだと　貴方もお父様と同じように利用されて殺されてしまう
They have been chosen.
彼らは選ばれたんだ
Mario!
マリオさん
Ocean sunfish
They have been chosen to put the world back on track.
この世界の間違いを正す者に選ばれたんだ
Ocean sunfish
Blowfish
Put the world back on track?
この世界が間違えてる
Fish Encyclopedia
After all, your brother is innocent.
だって　君の弟にはなんの罪もない
Yes. So, you're saving him, right?
そうよ　だから　貴方が助けてくれるんでしょう
That was the deal!
そういう約束だったわ
Yes, I will save him.
うん　助けてあげるよ
If you join them, as a chosen one.
君も選ばれた者として　行動を共にすればね
What are you up to?
何をしようとしているの
We're taking back the world.
世界を取り戻すのさ
No!
だめ　冠葉
Kanba!
お姉さまが気がつかれた
Masako woke up!
What happened to... me?
私は　いったい
Milady, it was a close call!
お嬢様　危なかったです
You've been hovering between life and death for three whole days because of the blowfish poison!
ふぐの毒で三日三晩生死の境を彷徨われてました
I am not taking that train.
私は　その列車には乗らないわ
イカレちまったぜー
ikarechimattaze
Everyone went nutso!
Uncrushable Man
イカレちまったぜ　どいつもこいつも
ikarechimattaze doitsu mo koitsu mo
Everyone went nutso! Every single one of you
ikarechimattaze yoru wo nurikaero
Everyone went nutso! Paint the town red
イカレちまったぜ　夜を塗り替えろ
お前一人だけじゃないぜ
omae hitori dake ja naize kodoku wo kanjite iruno wa
You're not the only one feeling lonely
孤独を感じているのは
omae hitori dake ja naize saji wo nagecha inaino wa
You're not the only one throwing in the towel
お前一人だけじゃないぜ
さじをなげちゃいないのは
warui koto bakari wa sou tsuzukiya shinai
Things will get better in time
悪い事ばかりは　そう続きやしない
くたばっていく前に
kutabatte iku mae ni chance
wo tsukande kaketemiro
Take a risk and seize the day
before you kick the bucket
チャンスを掴んで賭けてみろ
furui hanashi hikizuttemo
nannimo kawaccha ikanai
Clinging to ancient history
won't get you anywhere
古い話　引きずっても
何も変わっちゃいかない
heya no naka de nageite itemo hitotsu mo rikou nya naranai
Crying alone in your room ain't the brightest thing to do
部屋の中で　嘆いていても
一つも利口にゃならない
shirakechimatta radio no switch wo keshite
Turn off the boring radio broadcast
しらけちまったラジオのスイッチを消して
kanaami wo tobikoete yatsura
ga matteru basket court
Hop the fence to shoot
hoops with your buds
金網を飛び越えて
奴らが待ってるバスケットコート
ikarechimattaze shibireppanashi de
Everyone went nutso! Electrified the whole time
イカレちまったぜ　痺れっぱなしで
ikarechimattaze Love at first sight
Everyone went nutso! Love at first sight
イカレちまったぜ　Love at first sight
ikarechimattaze shibireppanashi de
Everyone went nutso! Electrified the whole time
イカレちまったぜ　痺れっぱなしで
ikarechimattaze Love at first sight
Everyone went nutso! Love at first sight
イカレちまったぜ　Love at first sight
ikarechimattaze doitsu mo koitsu mo
Everyone went nutso! Every single one of you
イカレちまったぜ　どいつもこいつも
ikarechimattaze yoru wo nurikaero
Everyone went nutso! Paint the town red
イカレちまったぜ　夜を塗り替えろ
Don't worry, you can count on me to save you.
心配するな　お前の事は必ず俺が救って見せる
Even if I have to turn the whole world against me.
この世界の全てを敵にしても
Lily Hoshino
Survival Strategy might as well be hanged for a penguin as a chicken.
生存戦略　毒を食らわば皿までも